<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Learningraku on Raku Programming</title>
    <link>https://ohmysummer.github.io/categories/learningraku/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Learningraku on Raku Programming</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>zh-cn</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 00:10:09 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ohmysummer.github.io/categories/learningraku/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>第二十一章. 结论</title>
      <link>https://ohmysummer.github.io/post/2018-09-21-%E7%AC%AC%E4%BA%8C%E5%8D%81%E4%B8%80%E7%AB%A0.-%E7%BB%93%E8%AE%BA/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2018 00:10:09 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohmysummer.github.io/post/2018-09-21-%E7%AC%AC%E4%BA%8C%E5%8D%81%E4%B8%80%E7%AB%A0.-%E7%BB%93%E8%AE%BA/</guid>
      <description>声明 本章翻译仅用于 Raku 学习和研究, 请支持电子版或纸质版。
第二十一章. 结论 Congratulations. You’ve made it to the end of the book. Some people estimate that only one-third of the readers of a technical book accomplish that feat. This book was only supposed to be 300 pages long, but I couldn’t decide how to leave out anything still included. Sorry about that. The 80 pages of exercise answers really sent me over the limit. If you’re reading this, send me an email noting your rarified status as a completist reader!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>第二十章. 高级话题</title>
      <link>https://ohmysummer.github.io/post/2018-09-20-%E7%AC%AC%E4%BA%8C%E5%8D%81%E7%AB%A0.-%E9%AB%98%E7%BA%A7%E8%AF%9D%E9%A2%98/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2018 00:10:09 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohmysummer.github.io/post/2018-09-20-%E7%AC%AC%E4%BA%8C%E5%8D%81%E7%AB%A0.-%E9%AB%98%E7%BA%A7%E8%AF%9D%E9%A2%98/</guid>
      <description>声明 本章翻译仅用于 Raku 学习和研究, 请支持电子版或纸质版。
第二十章. 高级话题 In such a short book I don’t have enough pages to show you everything that you can do. This chapter is a brief survey of some of the features I would have liked to explain in more detail. You now know these exist and you can investigate them further on your own.
在这么短的书中，我没有足够的页面向你展示你可以做的一切。本章简要介绍了一些我希望更详细解释的功能。你现在知道这些存在，你可以自己进一步研究它们。
单行 You can run raku one-liners. These are programs that you compose completely on the command line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>第十九章. 控制其他程序</title>
      <link>https://ohmysummer.github.io/post/2018-09-19-%E7%AC%AC%E5%8D%81%E4%B9%9D%E7%AB%A0.-%E6%8E%A7%E5%88%B6%E5%85%B6%E4%BB%96%E7%A8%8B%E5%BA%8F/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 00:10:09 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohmysummer.github.io/post/2018-09-19-%E7%AC%AC%E5%8D%81%E4%B9%9D%E7%AB%A0.-%E6%8E%A7%E5%88%B6%E5%85%B6%E4%BB%96%E7%A8%8B%E5%BA%8F/</guid>
      <description>声明 本章翻译仅用于 Raku 学习和研究, 请支持电子版或纸质版。
第十九章. 控制其它程序 有时你需要让其他程序为你做一些工作。 Perl 系列语言被称为“互联网的胶水”。开始一个著名的，稳定的，现有的程序比自己重新实现它更容易，更快。本章介绍了许多启动和控制外部程序的方法，以便根据你的意愿对其进行控制。
快速和容易 shell 例程是运行外部命令或程序的快捷方式。它接受参数并在 shell 中运行它，就像你自己输入它一样。此示例使用类 Unix 的 shell 命令列出所有文件：
shell( &#39;ls -l&#39; );  If you were on Windows you’d use a different command. There’s an implicit cmd /c in front of your command:
如果你在 Windows 上，你会使用不同的命令。命令前面有一个隐式的 cmd /c：
shell( &#39;dir&#39; ); # actually cmd /c dir  此命令的输出将转到程序输出所在的位置（只要你没有将标准输出或错误重定向到其他内容）。
你可以通过检查 $*DISTRO 变量来选择命令。 Distro 对象有一个 .is-win 方法，如果它认为你的程序在该平台上运行，则返回 True：
my $command = $*DISTRO.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>第十八章.  Supplies, Channels 和 Promises</title>
      <link>https://ohmysummer.github.io/post/2018-09-18-%E7%AC%AC%E5%8D%81%E5%85%AB%E7%AB%A0.-supplies-channels-%E5%92%8C-promises/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 00:10:09 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohmysummer.github.io/post/2018-09-18-%E7%AC%AC%E5%8D%81%E5%85%AB%E7%AB%A0.-supplies-channels-%E5%92%8C-promises/</guid>
      <description>声明 本章翻译仅用于 Raku 学习和研究, 请支持电子版或纸质版。
第十八章. Supplies, Channels 和 Promises Supplies and channels provide ways to send data from one part of a program to another. A Supply is a direct line of communication from a source of data to possibly many consumers. A Channel allows any part of your program to add data to a queue that any part of your program can read.
Supplies 和 channels 提供了将数据从程序的一部分发送到另一个程序的方法。 Supply 是从数据源到可能许多消费者的直接通信线。 Channel 允许程序的任何部分将数据添加到程序的任何部分都可以读取的队列中。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>第十七章. Grammars</title>
      <link>https://ohmysummer.github.io/post/2018-09-17-%E7%AC%AC%E5%8D%81%E4%B8%83%E7%AB%A0.-grammars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 00:10:09 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohmysummer.github.io/post/2018-09-17-%E7%AC%AC%E5%8D%81%E4%B8%83%E7%AB%A0.-grammars/</guid>
      <description>声明 本章翻译仅用于 Raku 学习和研究, 请支持电子版或纸质版。
第十七章. Grammars Grammars are patterns on a higher plane of existence. They integrate and reuse pattern fragments to parse and react to complicated formats. This feature is at the core of Raku in a very literal sense; the language itself is implemented as a grammar. Once you start using it you’ll probably prefer it to regexes for all but the most simple problems.
Grammars 是存在于更高层面上的模式。它们集成并重用模式片段来解析复杂的格式并做出反应。从字面意义上讲，这个功能是Raku的核心;语言本身是作为语法实现的。一旦你开始使用它，你可能更喜欢它除了最简单的问题之外的所有正则表达式。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>第十六章. 更漂亮的正则表达式</title>
      <link>https://ohmysummer.github.io/post/2018-09-16-%E7%AC%AC%E5%8D%81%E5%85%AD%E7%AB%A0.-%E6%9B%B4%E6%BC%82%E4%BA%AE%E7%9A%84%E6%AD%A3%E5%88%99%E8%A1%A8%E8%BE%BE%E5%BC%8F/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 00:10:09 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohmysummer.github.io/post/2018-09-16-%E7%AC%AC%E5%8D%81%E5%85%AD%E7%AB%A0.-%E6%9B%B4%E6%BC%82%E4%BA%AE%E7%9A%84%E6%AD%A3%E5%88%99%E8%A1%A8%E8%BE%BE%E5%BC%8F/</guid>
      <description>声明 本章翻译仅用于 Raku 学习和研究, 请支持电子版或纸质版。
第十六章. 更漂亮的正则表达式 You won’t see all the rest of the regular expression syntax in this chapter, but you’ll see the syntax you’ll use the most. There’s much more to patterns, but this should get you most of the way through common problems. With grammars (Chapter 17), the power of even simple patterns will become apparent.
在本章中，你不会看到所有其他正则表达式语法，但你将看到最常用的语法。模式有很多，但这应该可以解决常见问题。使用 grammars（第17章），即使是简单模式的威力也会变得明显。
量词 Quantifiers allow you to repeat a part of a pattern.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>第十五章. 正则表达式</title>
      <link>https://ohmysummer.github.io/post/2018-09-15-%E7%AC%AC%E5%8D%81%E4%BA%94%E7%AB%A0.-%E6%AD%A3%E5%88%99%E8%A1%A8%E8%BE%BE%E5%BC%8F/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 00:10:09 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohmysummer.github.io/post/2018-09-15-%E7%AC%AC%E5%8D%81%E4%BA%94%E7%AB%A0.-%E6%AD%A3%E5%88%99%E8%A1%A8%E8%BE%BE%E5%BC%8F/</guid>
      <description>声明 本章翻译仅用于 Raku 学习和研究, 请支持电子版或纸质版。
第十五章. 正则表达式 Regular expressions (or regexes) are patterns that describe a possible set of matching texts. They are a little language of their own, and many characters have a special meaning inside patterns. They may look cryptic at first, but after you learn them you have quite a bit of power.
Forget what you’ve seen about patterns in other languages. The Raku pattern syntax started over.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>第十四章. Junctions 和集合</title>
      <link>https://ohmysummer.github.io/post/2018-09-14-%E7%AC%AC%E5%8D%81%E5%9B%9B%E7%AB%A0.-junctions-%E4%B8%8E%E9%9B%86%E5%90%88/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Sep 2018 00:10:09 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohmysummer.github.io/post/2018-09-14-%E7%AC%AC%E5%8D%81%E5%9B%9B%E7%AB%A0.-junctions-%E4%B8%8E%E9%9B%86%E5%90%88/</guid>
      <description>声明 本章翻译仅用于 Raku 学习和研究, 请支持电子版或纸质版。
第十四章. Junctions 和集合 Junctions A Junction is a combination of values that is mostly indistinguishable from a single value. They have their roots in the math of quantum mechanics. You may have heard of Schrödinger’s cat, who is both dead and alive at the same time—an analogy that physicist used to show how ridiculous this all is. Well, the joke was on him.
Junction 是一组值，它们与单个值几乎无法区分。它们根植于于量子力学中的数学。你可能听说过薛定谔的猫，同一个时间它既死又活着 - 这个物理学家用来表示这一切是多么荒谬。那个笑话现在应在 Junction 身上了。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>第十三章. 角色</title>
      <link>https://ohmysummer.github.io/post/2018-09-13-%E7%AC%AC%E5%8D%81%E4%B8%89%E7%AB%A0.-%E8%A7%92%E8%89%B2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 00:10:09 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohmysummer.github.io/post/2018-09-13-%E7%AC%AC%E5%8D%81%E4%B8%89%E7%AB%A0.-%E8%A7%92%E8%89%B2/</guid>
      <description>声明 本章翻译仅用于 Raku 学习和研究, 请支持电子版或纸质版。
第十三章. 角色 角色是 mixins，可以增强你的类，就像它们的内容被定义在类里一样。一旦定义，它们的源实际上会被遗忘（与父类不同）。你可以使用角色来更改类，从现有类创建新类，以及增强单个对象。它们比继承更灵活，通常是更好的解决方案。角色用于代码重用，而类用于管理对象。
给类添加行为 构造一个空的 Butterfly 类。即使没有属性接收参数的值，你也可以为 .new 提供参数：
class Butterfly {} my $butterfly = Butterfly.new: :common-name(&#39;Perly Cracker&#39;);  现在给你的蝴蝶命名。名字应该是 Butterfly 类的一部分吗？名字不是对象. Hamadryas guatemalena 是蝴蝶的名字。 Guatemalan Cracker，Calicó 和 Soñadoracomún 也是蝴蝶的名字。这些都是同一只蝴蝶的名字。
注意 最终，你编写的代码必须在该语言框架内运行。语法有时会让你在认知上将事物分开。
A name is not a more specific version of something the class already does and it’s not limited to butterflies or butterfly-like things. Many dissimilar things can have a common name—animals, cars, food.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>第十二章. 类</title>
      <link>https://ohmysummer.github.io/post/2018-09-12-%E7%AC%AC%E5%8D%81%E4%BA%8C%E7%AB%A0.-%E7%B1%BB/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 00:10:09 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohmysummer.github.io/post/2018-09-12-%E7%AC%AC%E5%8D%81%E4%BA%8C%E7%AB%A0.-%E7%B1%BB/</guid>
      <description>声明 本章翻译仅用于 Raku 学习和研究, 请支持电子版或纸质版。
第十二章. 类 A class is the blueprint for an object and manages an object and its behavior. It declares attributes to define what an object will store and methods to define how an object can behave. Classes model the world in a way that makes it easier for your program to do its job.
类是对象的蓝图，用于管理对象及其行为。它声明属性以定义对象将存储的内容以及定义对象行为方式的方法。类以一种使程序更容易完成其工作的方式对世界建模。
I’m mostly going to ignore object-oriented analysis and design. This chapter is about the mechanism of classes and objects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>第十一章. 子例程</title>
      <link>https://ohmysummer.github.io/post/2018-09-11-%E7%AC%AC%E5%8D%81%E4%B8%80%E7%AB%A0.-%E5%AD%90%E4%BE%8B%E7%A8%8B/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 00:10:09 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohmysummer.github.io/post/2018-09-11-%E7%AC%AC%E5%8D%81%E4%B8%80%E7%AB%A0.-%E5%AD%90%E4%BE%8B%E7%A8%8B/</guid>
      <description>声明 本章翻译仅用于 Raku 学习和研究, 请支持电子版或纸质版。
第十一章. 子例程 Now it’s time for more sophisticated subroutines. You were introduced to them in Chapter 5 but you only saw enough to support the upcoming chapters. Now that you’ve seen Arrays and Hashes, there’s much more you can do with subroutine signatures.
现在是更复杂的子例程的时候了。你在第五章见过它们了，但你只看到足以支持即将到来的章节。现在你已经看过数组 和 哈希，你可以用子例程签名做更多的事情。
A Basic Subroutine When you run a subroutine you get some sort of result: the last evaluated expression. That’s the return value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>第十章. 使用模块</title>
      <link>https://ohmysummer.github.io/post/2018-09-10-%E7%AC%AC%E5%8D%81%E7%AB%A0.-%E4%BD%BF%E7%94%A8%E6%A8%A1%E5%9D%97/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 00:10:09 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohmysummer.github.io/post/2018-09-10-%E7%AC%AC%E5%8D%81%E7%AB%A0.-%E4%BD%BF%E7%94%A8%E6%A8%A1%E5%9D%97/</guid>
      <description>声明 本章翻译仅用于 Raku 学习和研究, 请支持电子版或纸质版。
第十章. 使用模块 Modules allow you to compartmentalize, distribute, and reuse code. Someone creates a general solution to something, then packages it so you can reuse it in your programs. Sometimes people make these modules available to everyone. You can find some Raku modules at https://modules.raku.org
You don’t have to understand the code inside a module to benefit from its features. You can usually follow the examples in its documentation even if it uses syntax that you haven’t already seen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>第九章. Associatives</title>
      <link>https://ohmysummer.github.io/post/2018-09-09-%E7%AC%AC%E4%B9%9D%E7%AB%A0.-associatives/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:10:09 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohmysummer.github.io/post/2018-09-09-%E7%AC%AC%E4%B9%9D%E7%AB%A0.-associatives/</guid>
      <description>声明 本章翻译仅用于 Raku 学习和研究, 请支持电子版或纸质版。
第九章. Associatives Associative 使用被称为键的任何名字索引到值。Associative是无序的，因为键没有相对顺序。其他语言具有类似的数据类型，它们称为关联数组，字典，散列，映射或类似的东西。有几种类型的专用关联数据结构，你已经使用了其中的一些。
Pairs A Pair has a single key and a value. You’ve already used these in their adverbial form, although you didn’t know they were Pairs. Create a Pair through general object construction with the name and value as arguments:
Pair 具有单个键和值。你已经以他们的副词形式使用了这些，虽然你不知道他们是 Pair。通过一般对象构造创建一个 Pair，名称和值作为参数：
my $pair = Pair.new: &#39;Genus&#39;, &#39;Hamadryas&#39;;  The =&amp;gt; is the Pair constructor. You don’t have to quote the lefthand side because the =&amp;gt; does that for you as long as it looks like a term:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>第八章. 文件和目录,输入和输出</title>
      <link>https://ohmysummer.github.io/post/2018-09-08-%E7%AC%AC%E5%85%AB%E7%AB%A0.-%E6%96%87%E4%BB%B6%E5%92%8C%E7%9B%AE%E5%BD%95%E8%BE%93%E5%85%A5%E5%92%8C%E8%BE%93%E5%87%BA/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 00:10:09 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohmysummer.github.io/post/2018-09-08-%E7%AC%AC%E5%85%AB%E7%AB%A0.-%E6%96%87%E4%BB%B6%E5%92%8C%E7%9B%AE%E5%BD%95%E8%BE%93%E5%85%A5%E5%92%8C%E8%BE%93%E5%87%BA/</guid>
      <description>声明 本章翻译仅用于 Raku 学习和研究, 请支持电子版或纸质版。
第八章. 文件和目录, 输入和输出 读写文本是许多你想要编写的程序的基础。你将数据存储在文件中并稍后检索该数据。本章是关于你需要执行此操作的所有功能。在此过程中，你将看到如何处理文件路径，移动文件以及使用目录。大多数情况都是使用你已经看过的相同语法完成的，但现在使用不同对象的类型。
本章中的许多任务可能由于程序之外的原因而失败。如果你希望在不同的目录中工作或希望某个文件存在，那么如果这些条件不为真，你可能不希望继续。这只是一个处理外部资源的程序的事实。
文件路径 IO::Path 对象表示文件路径。它知道如何根据文件系统的规则组合和拆分路径。只要路径的形式符合这些规则，该路径与实际存在的文件无关。你马上会看到如何处理丢失的文件。现在，在任何字符串上调用 .IO 将其转换为 IO::Path 对象：
my $unix-path = &#39;/home&#39;.IO; my $windows-path = &#39;C:/Users&#39;.IO;  要构建更深的路径，请使用 .add。你一次可以有多个层级。 .add 不会改变原始对象;它为你提供了一个新对象：
my $home-directory = $unix-path.add: &#39;hamadryas&#39;; my $file = $unix-path.add: &#39;hamadryas/file.txt&#39;;  如果要在那里构建路径，请赋值回原始对象：
$unix-path = $unix-path.add: &#39;hamadryas/file.txt&#39;;  二元赋值形式可能更有用：
$unix-path .= add: &#39;hamadryas/file.txt&#39;;  .basename 和 .parent 方法拆分路径：
my $home = &#39;/home&#39;.IO; my $user = &#39;hamadryas&#39;; # Str or IO::File will work my $file = &#39;file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>第七章. 当出错的时候</title>
      <link>https://ohmysummer.github.io/post/2018-09-07-%E7%AC%AC%E4%B8%83%E7%AB%A0.-%E5%BD%93%E5%87%BA%E9%94%99%E7%9A%84%E6%97%B6%E5%80%99/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 00:10:09 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohmysummer.github.io/post/2018-09-07-%E7%AC%AC%E4%B8%83%E7%AB%A0.-%E5%BD%93%E5%87%BA%E9%94%99%E7%9A%84%E6%97%B6%E5%80%99/</guid>
      <description>声明 本章翻译仅用于 Raku 学习和研究, 请支持电子版或纸质版。
第七章. 当出错的时候 Raku doesn’t always immediately give up when something goes wrong. It can fail softly. If the result of that problem doesn’t affect anything else in the program there’s no need to complain about it. However, the moment it becomes a problem that passive failure demands your attention.
This chapter shows you the error mechanisms and how to deal with them. You’ll see how to handle the problems that your program notices on your behalf as well as detect and report problems on your own.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>第六章. Positionals</title>
      <link>https://ohmysummer.github.io/post/2018-09-06-%E7%AC%AC%E5%85%AD%E7%AB%A0.-positionals/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 00:10:09 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohmysummer.github.io/post/2018-09-06-%E7%AC%AC%E5%85%AD%E7%AB%A0.-positionals/</guid>
      <description>声明 本章翻译仅用于 Raku 学习和研究, 请支持电子版或纸质版。
第六章. Positionals Your programming career is likely to be, at its heart, about moving and transforming ordered lists of some kind. Those might be to-do lists, shopping lists, lists of web pages, or just about anything else.
The broad term for such as list is Positional. Not everything in this chapter is strictly one of those; it’s okay to pretend that they are, though. The language easily interchanges among many of the types you’ll see in this chapter, and it’s sometimes important to keep them straight.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>第五章. 创建块</title>
      <link>https://ohmysummer.github.io/post/2018-09-05-%E7%AC%AC%E4%BA%94%E7%AB%A0.-%E5%88%9B%E5%BB%BA%E5%9D%97/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 00:10:09 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohmysummer.github.io/post/2018-09-05-%E7%AC%AC%E4%BA%94%E7%AB%A0.-%E5%88%9B%E5%BB%BA%E5%9D%97/</guid>
      <description>声明 本章翻译仅用于 Raku 学习和研究, 请支持电子版或纸质版。
第五章. 创建块 存储 Blocks 你可以把 Block 存储在一个变量中而不立即执行它。now 是一个内置项, 它能够给你一个 Instant。使用 := 进行绑定让右侧和左侧一样。这意味着 $block 和 Block 相同:
my $block := { now };  你不能对 $block 赋值, 因为没有涉及到容器。
你本没必要绑定到 Block 的。赋值也是可以的, 并且你可以在后面更改值:
my $block = { now }; $block = &#39;Hamadryas&#39;;  这不是那么有趣, 因为你可以在你能使用 now 的任何地方使用它。但是计算一个 1 分钟之后的时间的 Block 怎么样？给 now 加上 60 秒：
my $minute-later := { now + 60 };  当你执行 Block 的时候, 它的结果是最后一个被求值的表达式的值。使用 () 操作符执行 Block：</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>第四章. 字符串</title>
      <link>https://ohmysummer.github.io/post/2018-09-04-%E7%AC%AC%E5%9B%9B%E7%AB%A0.-%E5%AD%97%E7%AC%A6%E4%B8%B2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 00:10:09 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohmysummer.github.io/post/2018-09-04-%E7%AC%AC%E5%9B%9B%E7%AB%A0.-%E5%AD%97%E7%AC%A6%E4%B8%B2/</guid>
      <description>声明 本章翻译仅用于 Raku 学习和研究, 请支持电子版或纸质版。
第四章 字符串 Strings represent the text data in your program as Str objects. Raku’s facility with text data and its manipulation is one of its major attractions. This chapter focuses on the many ways that you can create Strs; for any job you have there’s likely a feature that makes that easy for you. Along with that you’ll see a bit about inspecting, extracting, and comparing text in preparation for loftier goals coming up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>第三章. 数字</title>
      <link>https://ohmysummer.github.io/post/2018-09-03-%E7%AC%AC%E4%B8%89%E7%AB%A0.-%E6%95%B0%E5%AD%97/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 00:10:09 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohmysummer.github.io/post/2018-09-03-%E7%AC%AC%E4%B8%89%E7%AB%A0.-%E6%95%B0%E5%AD%97/</guid>
      <description>声明 本章翻译仅用于 Raku 学习和研究, 请支持电子版或纸质版。
第三章. 数字 This chapter steps back from the breadth of the previous chapter to focus on the idea of numbers and their representation in your programs. Raku supports several types of numbers and works hard to keep them exact as long as it can.
本章从前一章的广度开始，重点介绍数字的概念及其在程序中的表示。 Raku 支持多种类型的数字，并且尽可能地努力保持它们的准确性。
Number Types Not all numbers are created alike. You’ve seen whole numbers, how to do basic mathematical operations on them, and how to compare them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>第二章. 猜数字</title>
      <link>https://ohmysummer.github.io/post/2018-09-02-%E7%AC%AC%E4%BA%8C%E7%AB%A0.-%E7%8C%9C%E6%95%B0%E5%AD%97/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 00:10:09 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohmysummer.github.io/post/2018-09-02-%E7%AC%AC%E4%BA%8C%E7%AB%A0.-%E7%8C%9C%E6%95%B0%E5%AD%97/</guid>
      <description>声明 本章翻译仅用于 Raku 学习和研究, 请支持电子版或纸质版。
第二章. 猜数字 You’re about to be thrown in the deep end. There are some basic things you need to know to write useful programs, and you’ll meet a lot of them in this chapter so you can write a number-guessing program by the end. It’s quite a bit to take in all at once but it should make the rest of the chapters more interesting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>第一章. 介绍</title>
      <link>https://ohmysummer.github.io/post/2018-09-01-%E7%AC%AC%E4%B8%80%E7%AB%A0.-%E4%BB%8B%E7%BB%8D/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2018 00:10:09 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ohmysummer.github.io/post/2018-09-01-%E7%AC%AC%E4%B8%80%E7%AB%A0.-%E4%BB%8B%E7%BB%8D/</guid>
      <description>声明 本章翻译仅用于 Raku 学习和研究, 请支持电子版或纸质版。
第一章. 介绍 本章是该语言的全貌图; 如果你还不了解正在发生的一切，请不要担心。担心如果你到了本书的最后，你仍然没有了解全部！有讲很多东西，所以将围绕一些话题，重新审视其他话题，并通过一些练习看看它们是如何融合在一起的 - 这真的都是关于实践的。
为什么是 Raku? 对于初学者，你要学习 Raku。你也可能通过使用这种语言来使得物有所值！
但是什么使这种语言变得有吸引力？ Perl 家族一直喜欢 DWIM-Do What I Mean。你经常做的事情应该很容易做，而最困难的事情应该是可能的。任何编程语言的用处都可以通过它解决问题的程度来衡量。
Raku 是一种出色的文本处理语言 - 甚至可能比 Perl 5 更好。正则表达式（第15章）有许多令人兴奋的新功能，可以更容易地匹配和提取文本。内置 grammar（第17章）功能允许你轻松编写复杂的规则来处理和响应文本。
渐进类型（第3章）允许你注释变量，并限制你可以存储的内容。例如，你可以指定数字必须是整数，正数或两个其他数字之间的数。你不必必须使用它（这是渐进的部分）。你将能够注释子例程接受什么以及它应该返回什么。这可以快速揭示数据边界的错误。
内置并发（第18章）功能允许你将问题分解为单独运行并可能同时运行的部分。该语言为你处理大部分内容。
惰性列表和无限列表允许你处理序列而无需过多复制或甚至一次拥有整个列表（第6章）。你可以轻松创建自己的无限惰性列表。
我可以继续前进，但是当你按照本书的方式工作时，你会遇到更多令人惊叹的功能。
有时你不想使用 Raku。没有语言能适用所有的工作。如果你更喜欢其他更好的东西，或者可以使用不同的工具更快地完成任务，那么对你来说更强大！但是，我希望本书可以帮助你在 Raku 中快速有效地完成你需要做的事情。
First Steps with the REPL REPL 是一个 Read-Evaluate-Print-Loop 的工具，提供交互式提示。 REPL 计算你键入的代码，显示结果，然后再次提示你。这是尝试代码片段的快速方法。当你运行不带参数的 raku 时，它会启动它的 REPL：
% raku To exit type &#39;exit&#39; or &#39;^D&#39; &amp;gt;  &amp;gt; 是等待你输入内容的提示。当你键入 Return 时，REPL 开始工作。通过使两个数字相加来尝试 REPL：
% raku &amp;gt; 2 + 2 4  如果出现错误，它会让你知道并再次提示你：</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>